I'm going to tell you about an affliction I suffer from.
سأخبركم عن مشكلة أعاني منها
And I have a funny feeling that quite a few of you
ولدي إحساس مضحك بأن بعضكم
suffer from it as well.
يعاني منها أيضًا
When I'm walking around an art gallery,
عندما أتمشى داخل معرض فنون
rooms and rooms full of paintings,
غرف وغرف مليئة باللوحات
after about 15 or 20 minutes,
بعد مرور ١٥ أو ٢٠ دقيقة
I realize I'm not thinking about the paintings.
أدرك أنيي لا أفكر في اللوحات
I'm not connecting to them.
لا أتواصل معها
Instead, I'm thinking about that cup of coffee
بالعكس، فإنني أفكر في كوب القهوة
I desperately need to wake me up.
الذي احتاجه بشدة ليوقظني
I'm suffering from gallery fatigue.
إنني أعاني من إعياء المعارض
How many of you out there suffer from --
كم منكم يعاني منه
yes. Ha ha, ha ha!
نعم هاها، هاها!
Now, sometimes you might last longer
والآن، قد تصمد أكثر من ٢٠ دقيقة
than 20 minutes, or even shorter,
في بعض الأحيان أو حتى أقل
but I think we all suffer from it. And do you have
ولكن أعتقد بأننا جميعًا نعاني منه. وهل تحسون
the accompanying guilt?
بالذنب المصاحب له؟
For me, I look at the paintings on the wall
بالنسبة لي، فأنا انظر إلى اللوحة المعلقة على الحائط
and I think, somebody has decided to put them there,
وأفكر بأن أحدًا ما قرر وضعها هناك
thinks they're good enough to be on that wall,
مؤمنًا بأنها جديرة بأن تكون على ذاك الجدار
but I don't always see it.
ولكني لا أرى السبب دائمًا
In fact, most of the time I don't see it.
في الواقع، أنا لا أرى السبب في معظم الأحيان
And I leave feeling actually unhappy.
وأخرج بإحساس بعدم السعادة
I feel guilty and unhappy with myself,
أحس بالذنب وعدم الرضى عن نفسي
rather than thinking there's something wrong with the painting,
بدلاً من أن افكر بأن هناك شيئاً غير مرض باللوحة
I think there's something wrong with me.
أفكر بأنني أعاني من خطب ما
And that's not a good experience, to leave a gallery like that.
وترك معرض بهذا الشكل ليس بالتجربة الجيدة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The thing is, I think we should give ourselves a break.
والحقيقة، أعتقد بأنه يجب علينا إعطاء نفسنا راحة
If you think about going into a restaurant,
حينما تفكر بالذهاب إلى مطعم
when you look at the menu, are you expected to order
عندما تنظر إلى قائمة الطعام، هل من المتوقع منك
every single thing on the menu?
أن تقوم بطلب كل ما فيها؟
No! You select.
لا ! فأنت تختار.
If you go into a department store to buy a shirt,
عندما تذهب إلى محل ملابس لشراء قميص
are you going to try on every single shirt
هل ستقوم بتجربة جميع القمصان في ذاك المحل
and want every single shirt?
وتريدها جميعًا؟
Of course not, you can be selective. It's expected.
بالطبع لا، ستكون انتقائي وهذا متوقع
How come, then, it's not so expected
فلماذا إذاً لا يكون متوقعاً
to be selective when we go to an art gallery?
أن نكون انتقائيين عندما نذهب إلى معرض فنون؟
Why are we supposed to have a connection with every single painting?
لماذا يفترض بنا أن نكون صلة مع جميع اللوح؟
Well I'm trying to take a different approach.
حسنًا أنا أحاول أخذ منحنى آخر
And there's two things I do:
وهناك شيئان أقوم بفعلهما
When I go into a gallery, first of all, I go quite fast,
عندما أذهب لمعرض أول شيء أقوم بفعله هو المشي بسرعة
and I look at everything, and I pinpoint the ones
والنظر إلى كل شي وأقوم بتحديد الأشياء
that make me slow down for some reason or other.
التي تدعوني للتمهل لسبب أو لآخر
I don't even know why they make me slow down, but something
لا أعلم لما تجعلني أتمهل ولكن يوجد شيء ما
pulls me like a magnet
يجذبني كمغناطيس
and then I ignore all the others, and I just go to that painting.
وعندها اتجاهل الباقي واتوجه لهذه اللوحة
So it's the first thing I do is, I do my own curation.
وأول شيء أقوم به هو القيام بالتمحيص الخاص بي
I choose a painting. It might just be one painting in 50.
أختار لوحة قد تكون لوحة واحدة في ٥٠
And then the second thing I do is I stand in front of that painting,
وبعدها أقوم بالوقوف أمام تلك اللوحة
and I tell myself a story about it.
وأقوم بإخبار نفسي قصة عنها
Why a story? Well, I think that we are wired,
لماذا قصة؟ حسنًا أعتقد بأننا مسلكين
our DNA tells us to tell stories.
يأمرنا الحمض النووي الخاص بنا بإخبار القصص
We tell stories all the time about everything,
فنحن نقوم بقص الحكايا عن كل شيء طوال الوقت
and I think we do it because the world is kind of a crazy, chaotic place,
وأعتقد بأننا نقوم بذلك لأن العالم مجنون نوعًا ما، مكان فوضوي
and sometimes stories, we're trying to make sense of the world a little bit,
وأحيانًا من خلال القصص نحاول فهم العالم قليلاً
trying to bring some order to it.
نحاول وضع نظام له
Why not apply that to our looking at paintings?
فلماذا لا نطبق ذلك لنظرنا إلى اللوح؟
So I now have this sort of restaurant menu
الآن لدي قائمة شبيهة بقائمة المطاعم نوعًا ما
visiting of art galleries.
زيارة متاحف الفنون
There are three paintings I'm going to show you now
هناك ثلاث لوحات سأقوم بعرضها عليكم الآن
that are paintings that made me stop in my tracks
وهي لوحات أجبرتني على التوقف عندها
and want to tell stories about them.
وأريد قص حكايا عنهم
The first one needs little introduction --
الأولى تحتاج لمقدمة قصيرة
"Girl with a Pearl Earring" by Johannes Vermeer,
"الفتاة ذات القرط الؤلؤي" بواسطة يوهانس فيرمير
17th-century Dutch painter.
رسام هولندي في القرن السابع عشر
This is the most glorious painting.
هذه اللوحة الأكثر روعة
I first saw it when I was 19,
رأيتها لأول مره عندما كنت في التاسعة عشر
and I immediately went out and got a poster of it,
وقمت بالخروج مباشرة وشراء ملصق لها
and in fact I still have that poster. 30 years later it's hanging in my house.
ومازلت في الحقيقة أحتفظ بذاك الملصق. مازال معلق في منزلي
It's accompanied me everywhere I've gone,
فكان مرافقي في كل مكان ذهبت إليه
I never tire of looking at her.
لم أمل يوماً من تأملها
What made me stop in my tracks about her to begin with
الذي جعلني أتوقف عندها من الأساس
was just the gorgeous colors he uses
هي الألوان الجميلة الذي استخدمها
and the light falling on her face.
والضوء الساطع على وجهها
But I think what's kept me still coming back
ولكن أعتقد الشيء الذي جعلني أستمر في العودة إليها
year after year is another thing, and that is
سنة بعد سنة، هو شيء أخر تماماً، ألا وهو
the look on her face, the conflicted look on her face.
نظرتها، النظرة المتضاربة على وجهها
I can't tell if she's happy or sad,
لا أستطيع الجزم ما إذا كانت سعيدة أم حزينة
and I change my mind all the time.
وأغير رأيي طوال الوقت
So that keeps me coming back.
وهذا يجعلني أعود دائماً
One day, 16 years after I had this poster on my wall,
يوماً ما، بعد ١٦ سنة من وضعي لهذا الملصق على الجدار
I lay in bed and looked at her,
استلقيت على السرير ونظرت إليها
and I suddenly thought, I wonder what
وفجأه بدأت بالتفكير
the painter did to her to make her look like that.
بما فعل الرسام لجعلها تبدو كذلك
And it was the first time I'd ever thought that
وكانت تلك المرة الأولى التي أفكر بهذا
the expression on her face is actually reflecting
فالتعبير الذي يغطي وجهها يعكس
how she feels about him.
إحساسها تجاهه
Always before I'd thought of it as a portrait of a girl.
كنت دائماً أنظر إليها كمجرد صورة لفتاة
Now I began to think of it as a portrait of a relationship.
والآن بدأت أنظر إليها كصورة لعلاقة
And I thought, well, what is that relationship?
وتساءلت بعدها ما هذه العلاقة؟
So I went to find out. I did some research and discovered,
فذهبت لأجد الجواب. وقمت ببعض البحث واكتشفت
we have no idea who she is.
بأننا ليس لدينا أدنى فكرة من تكون
In fact, we don't know who any of the models
في الحقيقة إننا لا نعلم أي من العارضات
in any of Vermeer's paintings are,
في أي من لوحات فيرمير
and we know very little about Vermeer himself.
وأننا نعرف الشيء القليل عن فيرمير نفسه
Which made me go, "Yippee!"
والذي جعلني سعيد جداً
I can do whatever I want, I can come up with whatever story I want to.
فأنا أستطيع الأن فعل ما يحلو لي. أستطيع أن أقوم بتأليف أي قصة أريد
So here's how I came up with the story.
والأن سأخبركم كيف قمت بتأليف هذه القصة
First of all, I thought,
قمت بالتفكير
I've got to get her into the house.
بأنه يجب علي جلبها للمنزل أولاً
How does Vermeer know her?
كيف عرفها فيرمير؟
Well, there've been suggestions that
حسناً، كان هناك تلميحات بأنها
she is his 12-year-old daughter.
قد تكون أبنته ذات الـ ١٢ سنة
The daughter at the time was 12 when he painted the painting.
أبنته كانت تبلغ من العمر ١٢ سنة في وقت رسمه لهذه اللوحة
And I thought, no, it's a very intimate look,
وفكرت بأنه لا يمكن أن تكون إبنته لأن نظرتها حميميه جداً
but it's not a look a daughter gives her father.
وهي نظرة لا تعطيها الأبنه لوالدها
For one thing, in Dutch painting of the time,
وفي ذاك الوقت، في اللوحة الهولندية
if a woman's mouth was open, it was indicating sexual availability.
إذا كان فم المرأة مفتوح، فهو يشير إلى توفرها جنسياً
It would have been inappropriate for Vermeer
فسيكون غير لائق لفيرمير
to paint his daughter like that.
بأن يرسم إبنته بهذا الشكل
So it's not his daughter, but it's somebody
فإذا هي ليست إبنته، ولكنها شخص ما
close to him, physically close to him.
قريب منه جسدياً
Well, who else would be in the house?
حسناً، من يمكن أن يكون في المنزل عدا إبنته؟
A servant, a lovely servant.
خادمة، خادمة جميلة.
So, she's in the house.
فإذا هي في المنزل
How do we get her into the studio?
كيف يمكننا جلبها إلى الأستوديو؟
We don't know very much about Vermeer,
فنحن لا نعرف الكثير عن فيرمير
but the little bits that we do know, one thing we know
ولكن نعرف بعض الأشياء وإحداها هو
is that he married a Catholic woman, they lived with her mother
أنه تزوج من إمرأة كاثوليكية وعاشوا مع والدتها
in a house where he had his own room
في منزل حيث كان له غرفته الخاصة
where he -- his studio. He also had 11 children.
حيث كان هو والأستوديو. وكان لديه أيضاً ١١ طفلاً
It would have been a chaotic, noisy household.
وبهذا سيكون بيتاً كاثوليكياً مليئاً بالإزعاج
And if you've seen Vermeer's paintings before,
وإذا كنت قد رأيت لوحات فيرمير سابقاً
you know that they're incredibly calm and quiet.
فستلاحظ بأنها كانت مليئة بالهدوء والسكينة بشكل لا يصدق
How does a painter paint such calm, quiet paintings with 11 kids around?
كيف يمكن لرسام أن يقوم برسم لوحات هادئة وساكنة كهذه مع وجود ١١ طفلاً في الجوار؟
Well, he compartmentalizes his life.
في الواقع، كان يجزء حياته
He gets to his studio, and he says, "Nobody comes in here.
يذهب إلى الأستوديو ويقول: "لا أحد يأتي إلى الداخل.
Not the wife, not the kids. Okay, the maid can come in and clean."
لا الزوجة ولا الأولاد. حسناً، يمكن للخادمة أن تأتي لتقوم بالتنظيف"
She's in the studio. He's got her in the studio, they're together.
هي الآن في الأستوديو. فقد أتى بها إلى الأستوديو والآن هم سوية
And he decides to paint her.
ويقرر أن يرسمها
He has her wear very plain clothes.
جعلها تلبس ملابس بسيطة جداً
Now, all of the women, or most of the women in Vermeer's other paintings
والآن، جميع النساء أو أغلب النساء في لوحات فيرمير
wore velvet, silk, fur, very sumptuous materials.
كانوا يلبسون المخمل والحرير والفراء وأشياء فاخرة جداً
This is very plain; the only thing that isn't plain
هذه بسيطة جداً والشيء الوحيد الغير بسيط
is her pearl earring.
هو قرطها الؤلؤي
Now, if she's a servant, there is no way she could afford
والآن، إذا كانت خادمة فليس هناك مجال أبداً بأن تتحمل تكلفة
a pair of pearl earrings.
زوج من أقراط الؤلؤ
So those are not her pearl earrings. Whose are they?
ولذلك هذه الأقراط ليست ملكاً لها. فلمن هي؟
We happen to know, there's a list of Catharina, the wife's clothes.
ومن المعلومات التي لدينا قائمة بملابس الزوجة كاثرينا
Amongst them a yellow coat with white fur,
ومن بينها معطف أصفر مع فراء أبيض
a yellow and black bodice,
وكورساج أصفر وأسود
and you see these clothes on lots of other paintings,
وترى هذه الملابس في عدد من لوحاته
different women in the paintings, Vermeer's paintings.
نساء مختلفين في لوحات فيرمير
So clearly, her clothes were lent to various different women.
وهو واضح جداً بأن ملابسها كانت تستعار من قبل نساء متعددات
It's not such a leap of faith to take
فإنه ليس من الغريب استنتاج
that that pearl earring actually belongs to his wife.
أن أقراط الؤلؤ ملك لزوجته
So we've got all the elements for our story.
الآن لدينا جميع عناصر قصتنا
She's in the studio with him for a long time.
هي معه في الأستوديو لوقت طويل
These paintings took a long time to make.
هذه اللوحات كانت تأخذ الكثير من الوقت لرسمها
They would have spent the time alone, all that time.
فمن المؤكد أنهم قضو كل ذلك الوقت بمفردهم
She's wearing his wife's pearl earring.
هي تلبس أقراط زوجته اللؤلؤية
She's gorgeous. She obviously loves him. She's conflicted.
إنها رائعة. من الواضح جداً أنها تحبه. إنها مليئة بالتعارضات
And does the wife know? Maybe not.
وهل تعلم الزوجة؟ من الممكن لا.
And if she doesn't, well --
وفي حال كانت لا تعلم، حسناً
that's the story.
هنا تكمن القصة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The next painting I'm going to talk about
اللوحة الثانية التي سأقوم بالتحدث عنها
is called "Boy Building a House of Cards" by Chardin.
تسمى "ولد يقوم ببناء منزل من البطاقات" شاردان
He's an 18th-century French painter best known for his still lifes,
وهو رسام فرنسي في القرن الثامن عشر ومعروف برسمه للأشياء الجامدة
but he did occasionally paint people.
ولكنه قام في بعض الأحيان برسم الأشخاص
And in fact, he painted four versions of this painting,
وفي الحقيقة، قام برسم أربع إصدارات من هذه اللوحة
different boys building houses of cards, all concentrated.
أولاد مختلفين يبنون البيوت من البطاقات، كلها مركزة
I like this version the best, because some of the boys
هذه النسخة المفضلة لدي، لأن بعض الأولاد
are older and some are younger, and to me, this one,
أكبر وبعضهم أصغر، وبالنسبة لي، هذه
like Goldilocks's porridge, is just right.
مثل المعتدل في العصيدة
He's not quite a child, and he's not quite a man.
فهو ليس طفل وليس رجل في نقس الوقت
He's absolutely balanced between innocence and experience,
هو معتدل تماما ما بين البراءة والخبرة
and that made me stop in my tracks in front of this painting.
وهذا ما جعلني أتوقف أمام هذه اللوحة
And I looked at his face. It's like a Vermeer painting a bit.
ونظرت إلى هذا الوجه. إنه كلوحة فيرمير قليلاً
The light comes in from the left, his face is bathed
الضوء يأتي من اليسار، وجهه مغطى
in this glowing light. It's right in the center of the painting,
بهذا الضوء اللامع. إنه في منتصف اللوحة بالضبط
and you look at it, and I found that when I was looking at it,
وتنظر إليه واكتشفت أنه عندما كنت أنظر إليه
I was standing there going,
كنت أقف هناك وأقول
"Look at me. Please look at me."
"أنظر إلي. أرجوك أنظر إلي"
And he didn't look at me. He was still looking at his cards,
ولم ينظر إلي. فكان مازال ينظر إلى بطاقاته
and that's one of the seductive elements of this painting is,
وهذا إحدى العناصر المغرية في هذه اللوحة
he's so focused on what he's doing that he doesn't look at us.
فهو في قمة التركيز فيما يعمل لدرجة أنه لا ينظر إلينا
And that is, to me, the sign of a masterpiece,
وهذا في نظري علامة التحفة الفنية
of a painting when there's a lack of resolution.
للوحة عندما لا يكون هناك حزم
He's never going to look at me.
هو لن ينظر إلي أبداً
So I was thinking of a story where,
فكنت أفكر في قصة حيث
if I'm in this position, who could be there looking at him?
إذا ما كنت في هذا الوضع، من من الممكن أن ينظر إلي؟
Not the painter, I don't want to think about the painter.
ليس الرسام، لا أريد التفكير بالرسام.
I'm thinking of an older version of himself.
أفكر في نسخة أكبر منه.
He's a man, a servant, an older servant looking at this younger servant,
فهو رجل، خادم، خادم أكبر ينظر إلى الخادم الصغير
saying, "Look at me. I want to warn you about
قائلاً: "أنظر إلي. أريد أن أنذرك
what you're about to go through. Please look at me."
بما ستخوضه قريباً. أرجوك أنظر إلي"
And he never does.
ولم ينظر أبداً
And that lack of resolution, the lack of resolution in "Girl with a Pearl Earring" --
وإنعدام الحل في "الفتاة ذات القرط الؤلؤي"
we don't know if she's happy or sad.
فإننا نجهل ما إذا كانت سعيدة أم حزينة
I've written an entire novel about her,
كتبت رواية كاملة عنها
and I still don't know if she's happy or sad.
ومازلت لا أعلم ما إذا كانت سعيدة أم حزينة
Again and again, back to the painting,
مرة بعد مرة، أعود للوحة
looking for the answer, looking for the story to fill in that gap.
أبحث عن الجواب، أبحث عن القصة لملئ الفراغ
And we may make a story, and it satisfies us momentarily,
فيمكننا كتابة قصة ترضينا لوقت من الزمن
but not really, and we come back again and again.
ولكن ليس كلياً فنعود مرة بعد مرة لنفس السؤال
The last painting I'm going to talk about
آخر لوحة سأتكلم عنها
is called "Anonymous" by anonymous. (Laughter)
تسمى "مجهول" من قبل مجهول. (ضحك)
This is a Tudor portrait bought by the National Portrait Gallery.
هذه صورة شخصية لأحد أفراد عائلة تودر والتي قام معرض الصور الوطني بشراءها
They thought it was a man named Sir Thomas Overbury,
قاموا بشراءها عندما كان اسمها سير توماس اوفيربيري
and then they discovered that it wasn't him,
وبعدها أكتشفوا انها لم تكن هو
and they have no idea who it is.
ولم تكن لديهم أدنى فكرة من يكون
Now, in the National Portrait Gallery,
الآن، في معرض الصور الوطني
if you don't know the biography of the painting,
إذا لم تكن تعرف السيرة الذاتية للصورة
it's kind of useless to you.
فلا قيمة لها عندك
They can't hang it on the wall, because they don't know who he is.
لا يمكنهم وضعها في المعرض لأنهم لا يعرضون من يكون
So unfortunately, this orphan spends most of his time in storage,
وللأسف، فهذا اليتيم يقضي معظم وقته في المخزن
along with quite a number of other orphans,
مع عدد ليس بالقليل من اليتامى الآخرين
some of them some beautiful paintings.
بعضهم لوحات جميلة
This painting made me stop in my tracks for three reasons:
أوقفتني هذه اللوحة لثلاث اسباب:
One is the disconnection between his mouth
أحداها هو عدم الترابط بين فمه
that's smiling and his eyes that are wistful.
المبتسم وعيناه الحزينتان
He's not happy, and why isn't he happy?
هو ليس سعيد ولماذا هو ليس كذلك؟
The second thing that really attracted me
السبب الثاني الذي شد انتباهي
were his bright red cheeks.
هو وجنتيه النضرة المحمرة
He is blushing. He's blushing for his portrait being made!
هو يشعر بالخجل. يشعر بالخجل لرسم صورته الشخصية!
This must be a guy who blushes all the time.
هذا الرجل لابد أنه شخص يشعر بالخجل طوال الوقت.
What is he thinking about that's making him blush?
ما الذي يفكر فيه الآن ليحمر خجلاً؟
The third thing that made me stop in my tracks
والسبب الثالث الذي جعلني اتوقف عند هذه اللوحة
is his absolutely gorgeous doublet.
هو صدريته الرائعة للغاية
Silk, gray, those beautiful buttons.
حرير، رمادي، وأزرة جميلة
And you know what it makes me think of,
وتعرفون ما الذي تجعلني أفكر به
is it's sort of snug and puffy; it's like a duvet spread over a bed.
هو أنها نوعاً ما دافئة ومنتفخة كما لو أنها لحاف منتشر على سرير
I kept thinking of beds and red cheeks,
استمريت بالتفكير بالأسرة والخدود الحمراء
and of course I kept thinking of sex when I looked at him,
وبالطبع استمريت بالتفكير بالجنسخلال نظري إليه
and I thought, is that what he's thinking about?
وفكرت، هل هذا ما يفكر فيه؟
And I thought, if I'm going to make a story,
وفكرت، إذا كنت سأكتب قصة
what's the last thing I'm going to put in there?
ماذا سيكون آخر شيء أضعه فيها؟
Well, what would a Tudor gentleman be preoccupied with?
حسناً، ما الذي يمكن أن يشغل نبيل من نبلاء التودر؟
And I thought, well, Henry VIII, okay.
وفكرت حسناً هنري الثامن
He'd be preoccupied with his inheritance, with his heir.
قد يكون مشغولاً بميراثه وخليفته
Who is going to inherit his name and his fortune?
من سيرث اسمه وثروته؟
You put all those together, and you've got your story
تضع كل هذه الأمور سوية وبعدها تجد قصتك
to fill in that gap that makes you keep coming back.
لملئ الفجوة التي تجبرك للعودة مراراً وتكراراً
Now, here's the story.
والآن، إليكم القصة
It's short.
انها قصيرة
"Rosy"
"روزي"
I am still wearing the white brocade doublet Caroline gave me.
ما زلت أرتدي الصدرية ذات الديباج الأبيض التي أعطتها كارولين لي
It has a plain high collar, detachable sleeves
إنها مكونة من الياقة المرتفعة العادية والأكمام القابلة للفصل
and intricate buttons of twisted silk thread,
والأزرار المثبته بخيوط الحرير الملتوية
set close together so that the fit is snug.
موضوعة بالقرب من بعضها البعض لتتناسب بدفئ
The doublet makes me think of a coverlet on the vast bed.
تجعلني الصدرية أفكر بغطاء سرير على سرير كبير جداً
Perhaps that was the intention.
ربما كان هذا القصد
I first wore it at an elaborate dinner her parents held in our honor.
أرتديته للمرة الأولى في عشاء عقده والديها على شرفنا
I knew even before I stood up to speak
وعرفت حتى قبل أن أقوم للحديث
that my cheeks were inflamed.
أن وجنتي كانت محمرة بحرارة
I have always flushed easily, from physical exertion,
لكنت دوماً سريع الذوبان من المجهود البدني
from wine, from high emotion.
من النبيذ، من المشاعر العالية
As a boy, I was teased by my sisters and by schoolboys,
حينما كنت صبياً، كنت امازح من قبل اخواتي وأطفال المدرسة
but not by George.
ولكن ليس من قبل جورج
Only George could call me Rosy.
كان جورج فقط من يستطيع أن يدعوني روزي
I would not allow anyone else.
لم أكن أسمح لأي أحد آخر
He managed to make the word tender.
كان يستطيح جعل الكلمة رقيقة ولطيفة
When I made the announcement, George did not
حينما قمت بإعلان الخبر، لم يتغير جورج
turn rosy, but went pale as my doublet.
للون الأحمر ولكن بدا شاحباً كما كان لون صدريتي
He should not have been surprised.
لم يكن من المفروض أن يفاجأ
It has been a common assumption
لقد كان توقعاً شائعاً
that I would one day marry his cousin.
بأنني يوماً ما سأتزوج من قريبه
But it is difficult to hear the words aloud.
ولكن كان من الصعب سماع الكلمات عالياً
I know, I could barely utter them.
أعرف ذلك لأنني بالكاد أستطيع نطقها
Afterwards, I found George on the terrace overlooking the kitchen garden.
بعد ذلك، وجد جورج جالساً في الشرفة المطلة على حديقة المطبخ
Despite drinking steadily all afternoon, he was still pale.
ومع أنه كان يشرب بثبات طوال الظهيرة، كان مايزال شاحباً
We stood together and watched the maids cut lettuces.
وقفنا سوية نشاهد الخادمات يقطعن الخس
"What do you think of my doublet?" I asked.
سألته: "ما رأيك بصدريتي؟"
He glanced at me. "That collar looks to be strangling you."
نظر إلي نظرة خاطفة وقال: "يبدو أن هذه الصدرية تخنقك"
"We will still see each other," I insisted.
"سنستمر برؤية بعضنا البعض" أصريت
"We can still hunt and play cards and attend court.
"ما زال باستطاعتنا الصيد ولعب الورق وحضور المحكمة
Nothing need change."
لا شيء يحتاج التغيير"
George did not speak.
لم ينطق جورج
"I am 23 years old. It is time for me to marry
"بلغت الـ ٢٣ من العمر. يجب علي أن أتزوج
and produce an heir. It is expected of me."
وانجاب وريث. أنه متوقع مني"
George drained another glass of claret and turned to me.
تناول جورج كأساً آخر من الكلاريت والتفت إلي
"Congratulations on your upcoming nuptials, James.
تهانينا على الأعراص القادمة يا جيمس
I'm sure you'll be content together."
أنا متأكد بأنكم ستكونون مرتاحين سوية
He never used my nickname again.
لم يستخدم لقبي مجداداً
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)